# **Oscar Torres**

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

# **Profile**

Passionate software developer, open to learn as much as I can, Committed to utilizing my skills to further the mission of a company. Knowledgeable in modern JavaScript (ECMAS6+), React, Redux, Express, NodeJS and MySQL. Able to effectively manage pre-processors as LESS and SASS as much as pure CSS. Bilingual.

Experience using Styled components (React), consuming APIS (JS) and CSS frameworks as tailwind for responsive designs.

# **Employment History**

# Front end developer, Tailorsoft, Remote

FEBRUARY 2021 - PRESENT

Implemented Typescript on a React project along unit and implementation testing with Jest and react-testing-library and end-end testing with cypress.

Discussed technical requirements and estimates with clients while code reviewing work from my peers.

#### Full Stack developer, SIICOING, Cali

JUNE 2020 - FEBRUARY 2021

- Redesigned the front-end to make the UX friendlier to the users and got a very good feedback from the users.
- Sped up the processes and performance of the application.
- Organized and prioritized work to complete assignments in a timely, efficient manner.
- Maintenance of MySQL databases

# Education

#### Full Stack Developer, Henry, Remote

NOVEMBER 2020 - PRESENT

- JavaScript and ECMAS6+
- React
- Redux as a state management library.
- NodeJs
- Express
- · Relational databases SQL
- Git

### Advanced course of React, Platzi

AUGUST 2021 - SEPTEMBER 2021

Reinforced knowledge on React Hooks, testing with Jest and Cypress, common design patterns for React and styling with styled components

# Courses

#### Basic course of Python, Platzi

SEPTEMBER 2021 - SEPTEMBER 2021

#### **Details**

+57 (304)-528-8108 oscardtorres@hotmail.com

#### **Portfolio**

**GitHub** 

LinkedIn

Weather-App Project

## Languages

Fluent in English

Native in Spanish

#### Skills

Agile and Scrum

React

Redux

Express.js

Git

NodeJS

Cypress

Jest